hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and on this podcast I
show coaches course creators trainers
and mentors how to scale their
businesses using online tools direct
response marketing artificial
intelligence and much more now today I
want to talk about the right and the
wrong ways to use AI in your business AI
is here to stay it's only getting more
powerful and I'll tell you earlier this
year I told people like be careful using
AI now I'm I'm saying you got to use it
on everything because um it's gotten so
much better it's it's improved so much
and so one of the first things that I
want to mention is is that chat GPT plus
gives you a lot of great features to use
but even the free version of chat GPT is
incredible to use and so make sure if
you've never used AI before get an
account with chat GPT and start using it
and how can we use AI well the number
one way is using it as a brainstorming
tool this is how I use it is I help it I
use it to come up with ideas it
basically uh I'm able to filter a lot of
my data through it so I have a a a
platform of software that takes all of
my trainings all of my coaching
everything that I teach on and it
transcribes it and then I take those
transcripts and I'm able to ask the AI
questions about the things that I've
taught on and so what this does is I
have what I've
taught transcribed into words the AI
then reads those words and then is able
to filter different outputs as far as
ideas such as what are the best topics
to talk about on Instagram reals What
are certain patterns what are things
that are similar to things can you break
down a certain workflow can you analyze
this piece of content and it can help
you with your market research give you
ideas for lead magnets outlines help you
write sales copy come up with content
ideas and much more and these are a lot
of the things that I know a lot of
coaches and mentors are like I just
don't know what to do
well here's the cool part about it is
that when you use an AI strategy
correctly which we're going to be
talking about in this training right
here and then and then in this uh
podcast episode you can feel confident
in the outputs that come with it but you
do want to learn to also tap into your
intuition intuition is a huge part of
using AI the right way that I think is
missed by a lot of people when you're
using it for your marketing so for me
what I do is I have the AI give me a
bunch of ideas instead getting
overwhelmed by it I just skim the ideas
that it gives me and whatever pops out
at me there's a thing called the
reticular activating system in our brain
and what the reticular activating system
is it's actually part of our nervous
system to where anything that is related
to what we care about and are focusing
on stands out to us and it can
physically create a sensation that stuff
is actually popping out of the screen or
on the page to you when you start to
learn how to do it the way that most of
us have experienced a reticular
activating system is that like when you
buy a car you see that same model of car
everywhere that you go well with
marketing and maybe you're listening to
this right now you see that AI is
everywhere and you're starting to
understand all these different things
about AI once you start focusing in on
the right things in your business your
intuitive factors start coming in and so
you have the AI which is very logical it
really doesn't understand intuition at
all and then you have your human factor
that you add on top of it that's the
right way to use the artificial
intelligence so the way that I've always
used AI is I will tune my nervous system
my mind towards what my end goal is okay
so I get clear on what is the end goal
and the ultimate end goal of anytime
we're using AI in our business two
things this really in my business
there's two things that are most
important to me at all times number one
How can I get the people who listen to
me the most Financial
gains in their life okay so that's
number one what's going to move them
from where they are to maximizing
Financial gains in their life okay
number two what is going to get the
people who follow me to
buy all of my stuff that I have to offer
and create the most Financial gains in
my life and when we combine those two
things together and basically the stuff
that is people are going to buy the most
aligns perfectly with what's also going
to deliver people the most results high
that's high integrity right there that's
also High profit that's a great strategy
for business and that's what I tune
everything that I do in my business
around so now when I'm using the AI I'm
thinking about that and I'm not really
necessarily thinking about the money
side of it most of the time that's more
the highlevel Strategic side but when
I'm looking at the AI I'm thinking about
okay what is going to get my clients the
most results
okay and what is the number one thing as
well that they desire to learn the most
about so those are two very important
things to think about now what do they
desire the most because when you can tap
into people's desires you can lead them
to the thing that's going to produce a
result unfortunately some of the best
coaches in the world don't know how to
do this they have great information they
know how to help people but they
actually lack one of the key elements of
being a leader which is knowing what
motivates people what do they desire the
most what is their deepest desire and it
might be separated from the actual
result that they're coming to you for
somebody's desire might be very
different from that and so you got to
learn to marry those two together and
walk that tight rope when you can learn
to then walk that tight RPP you can tune
your particular activating system around
what people want and now when we ask the
AI to give us ideas
for lead magnets for content for podcast
episodes for YouTube videos we're
already thinking of okay what is going
to produce this result now you got to
learn how to understand who your target
client is what do they actually want and
what does produce those results and that
does come from experience that's
extrapolated out based on the actual
experience that you have the experience
that produces result results in the
lives of the people that you work with
and so if you're not producing results
in people's lives or you've never
produced a certain kind of a result that
is going to be one of the first things
to look at is what actually produces
those results and you start to find a
group of people that you can get results
with for me in my life and in my
business for the last 21 years I've been
helping and building mentoring and
coaching businesses so I know what gets
results I also know what beginners
struggle with that stop them from
getting results now often times what
beginners struggle with that stops them
from getting results isn't the same as
what they actually want and if I just
lead with what they need this is key
right here okay if I lead with what
people
need
only I will not have the influence and
the leadership
capability with the people that I'm
leading because I'm merely dictating and
telling them what they need but I
haven't tapped into their desire factors
so when you can learn to marry the
desire factor which ultimately that
builds trust when somebody can trust me
as a leader and I need to prove myself
to be trustworthy and I need to be
somebody who is trustworthy when
somebody trusts me as a leader now when
I lead them to the thing that they need
they are more likely
to take action on it to do it and
ultimately to see results so really the
number one most important thing is
figuring out what do people desire and
how can I build trust in their mind that
I can deliver those results and the way
that we do that is we create content we
create trainings I I figure out what is
the area that people want to learn that
they're struggling with what are they
wanting to grow in in their businesses
and what can help them produce those
maximized results and then I start
delivering valuable
information to people
using this exact same framework that I
just talked about with that I then bring
that over to the artificial intelligence
I also bring the transcripts of those
same trainings so this is the other key
to it you bring the transcripts of those
trainings and you have the AI analyze
those transcripts and understand what
the subject matter is so once the AI
understands the subject matter now it
can start to brainstorm St exactly what
the needs desires goals and main things
that are going to produce results in
people's lives and businesses is going
to be and so now when I'm brainstorming
and I'm coming up with these ideas I can
feel confident that because the AI I've
now tuned it to the things that are in
alignment with what those desires are
and the way that we do that is I take
the transcripts of my training I can
literally take the transcript of this
training right here this podcast episode
bring it into the artificial
intelligence and start to ask it
questions and I actually want to show
you a demonstration of how we do this on
screen right now if you're watching on
the YouTube version we're about uh 9
minutes and 47 seconds into it and I'm
going to pull up on screen a transcript
in how we use AI to be able to do really
really cool things with it okay so
here's a transcript of a training that I
did with my coaching group on Monday
this week this was the training that I
did with my coaching group right here I
was teaching an an incredible topic um
and and it gives me a summary of it
about the importance of creating and
launching new offers and how to stay
consistent with those different offers
planning ahead copywriting how to
strategize all this it was a big
strategy call okay I have the transcript
right here now built into otter AI they
have ai chat which is really really cool
so I can now go in and I can say
generate me 20 pieces of content for
Instagram reals I can make with what is
taught in this session this now gives me
ideas for Instagram reals I can also go
in here generate me 20
YouTube video titles I can record based
on this training transcript okay and so
this built right into otter AI
is able to give me these different
outputs the number one activity that
grows your business how to plan your
business growth in 14-day Cycles
eliminate time wasting activities the
power of rotating offers to consistently
grow your email list that's a really
good one take this and map out a
detailed outline of this
YouTube video okay so this is the AI
that's actually built into otter AI but
you could do this with any sort of AI
software but I love that this is built
right into otter I can literally just
ask this without having to go into
another application and it uses the claw
uh engine behind it here's a detailed
outline of the YouTube video The Power
of rotating offers consistently to grow
your email list introduction importance
of growing your email list overview of
key strategy the problem with one offer
businesses power of rotating offers how
to implement this strategy case study of
how I've done this this is amazing
literally this could be a whole training
right here that I can do and maybe I
will I might record this as a YouTube
video right there so that gives me a lot
of great ideas now take this outline and
translate it into 20 Instagram reels
okay now this gives me 20 ideas for
Instagram reels while relying on one
single offer can stagnate your business
the echo chamber effect of promoting the
same offer over and over again how to
identify your core offer the list goes
on and you can see that based on my
actual transcript it's able to do that
and so that's one of the key ways that I
love using AI another thing that you can
do if you don't want to invest in
something like otter AI there's a couple
of different tools notebook LM is really
really
cool and it allows you to pull into it
any sort of YouTube video that you might
have you can pull a YouTube video in
Notebook LM let me go here in Notebook
LM and pull this up
okay notebook lm. goole.com and
if I go ahead and I can take a YouTube
video I can go to any YouTube video that
I've uploaded to
YouTube and immediately start asking
questions about the transcript of that
YouTube video so for
instance here
is a YouTube video that I did $40,000
month strategy right here I'm going to
add this into
YouTube okay now I can start to ask it
questions and so I can start asking
questions of the YouTube video by
pasting it as a source right here it can
also generate me a podcast any questions
I want what is the most important
aspect of getting new clients in a
business and I can start to develop this
out I can even go here you know generate
me 20 ideas for YouTube videos that
could be part two of this
video here we go I can take my YouTube
videos and be able to do this and the AI
is literally going to give me these
ideas it's just going to generate them
for
me using notebook
LM
amazing it's thinking really hard on
this one here we go all right psychology
persuasion how to ethically influence
buying decisions crafting an
irresistible offer beyond great
information building trust with free
value mastering the artst storytelling
overcoming sales objective
great map out and outline for a video
about this this is one of my key things
that I'll do is I'll have it take the
video and then I'll have it start to map
out an outline for a video and that
starts to expand the ideas together this
is one of my top ways of coming up with
ideas as I literally just have it
brainstorm and generate ideas and then I
have it map out um outline ideas and
then take those outlines and turn them
into other things right here okay uh
generate me 20 pieces of Instagram reels
based on this outline and I can
literally paste the outline below that
as well as part of the question whoops I
think it's too long for the question so
we'll just do that right there okay
generate me 20 pieces of Instagram reels
based on this
outline and I could also save this over
to the note as well I can save this uh
as a
note which is really really cool convert
all notes to a sour SCE now the note
becomes a source that it can start to
base itself off of that's amazing so now
it can actually pull up ideas based on
that outline right there okay objection
versus opportunity so these are all
different ways that I love to use
notebook LM is free that you can use you
can also go into um YouTube any YouTube
video gives you access to the
transcripts if I pull up a YouTube video
right here
I can go over to this YouTube video
here pull it up on screen and if I
scroll down to
more I can click on show
transcript and now here's the transcript
right there this is actually what
notebook LM is pulling from toggle
timestamps I can copy this transcript
and I can use it in any other version of
AI that I want like chat GPT or grock or
Claude or different things like that you
know know generate me 20 ideas
for lead magnets to promote my business
based on this transcript so 99% of what
I do with AI is I'm literally pulling
transcripts of what I'm talking about
and having it generate additional ideas
based on those transcripts and one of
the keys that I love is actually pulling
transcripts of Q&A sessions actual Q&A
sessions that I'm spending time with
people doing Q&A with them and then by
leveraging that Q&A I'm able to answer
those questions in additional pieces of
content let's see AI powered marketing
starter kit 10-step guide to building a
10K coaching business Niche Discovery
worksheet again these are actually great
ideas for lead magnets right here so AI
is your tool to be able to come up with
ideas and it's what we use in my
business to come up with 99% of the
ideas now that we do I take my own
experience and what I know how to do
into the training into the teaching but
the AI helps me brainstorm those ideas
and what angles to take with stuff and
it's really intelligent and really
effective at doing that okay listen if
you're somebody that wants to grow your
coaching business to get more clients
and make more money I'd love to work
with you in our client growth
accelerator program we work with coaches
and mentors every week to scale their
businesses to making multiple six
figures and we have a proven system
that'll work for you with that you can
watch below there's a link to a training
all about how to get 10 to 20 brand new
clients in your business and how to work
with us in the client growth accelerator
program click the link check that out
I'll see you in next week's episode of
The Grow Your Life podcast we'll talk
soon have a good one
[Applause]
[Music]